你在画什么呢
What are you drawing over there?
设计能为通往平行宇宙的
A hypothetical containment field
飞盘大小的虫洞
for a frisbee-sized wormhole
做为防护措施的安全禁锢场
that could serve as a portal to a parallel universe.
你个小笨蛋呆瓜
Oh, you silly doodlebug.
许多科学家认为
You know, a lot of scientists believe
与其他生命体有接触
that making contact with other life-forms
可能对人类造成巨大灾难
would probably not end well for us.
莱纳德  飞盘大小的虫洞而已
It's a frisbee-sized wormhole, Leonard.
用飞盘就能堵上了  别紧张
You can block it with a Frisbee. Calm down.
你是想我帮你造出来吗
Do you expect me to build this?
我是想你擦擦嘴角的布丁  大家再见
I expect you to wipe the pudding off your chin. Gentlemen.
你们有注意到谢尔顿每天
Have you guys ever noticed that Sheldon
都会准时在2点45分不知去向吗
always disappears every day at 2:45?
是吗
Really?
他可能只是去拉大号吧
He probably just goes to the bathroom.
他拉大号的时间是早上8点
Actually, no, he goes to the bathroom at 8:00 A.M.
没拉干净  则下午1点45再一趟
With optional follow-ups at 1:45
周五吃高纤维  晚上7点10分还拉
and 7:10 on high-fiber Fridays.
你居然都能记得了  真悲哀
It's sad that you know that.
这只是我悲哀的冰山一角呢
Oh, that's just the tip of the sadness iceberg.
我在看他公布的行程表
I'm looking at his public calendar.
2点45到3点05  没行程
2:45 to 3:05, nothing.
昨天同一时间  没行程
Yesterday, 2:45 to 3:05, nothing.
上周  也没行程
Last week, nothing.
上个月  这时间也没行程
Last month, nothing.
他总是把这段时间给空出来
He never has anything booked during that time.
每天都有着不为人知的20分钟
20 minutes a day, completely unaccounted for.
我们应该查查他到底上哪了
We should figure out where he goes.
好兴奋刺激哦
Ooh, this is exciting.
跟我举办的
Like one of my classic
神秘谋杀游戏晚餐派对一样
murder mystery dinner parties.
是啊  那派对谋杀了我
Right, the case of who murdered
三个美好的周六夜晚
three Saturday nights of my life?
库萨帕里上校在厨房中用橄榄渣杀的人
Colonel Koothrapali in the kitchen with the olive spread.
是高档橄榄酱
It was tapenade
你们俩去死吧
and you guys suck.
今天工作如何
So, how was work today?
我整个下午都忙着在生成
Well, I spent most of the afternoon growing
同位素纯水晶来探测微中子
isotopically pure crystals for neutrino detection.
听起来很有意思啊
That sounds like fun.
是啊  没错
Yeah, it was.
那就好  我猜对了
Oh, good, I guessed right.
在跟谁发消息呢
Who you talking to?
就学校的一个同学啦
Oh, just this guy I met at school.
行  我们还是情侣  对吧
Oh, great. We're still dating, right?
别乱想  只是朋友而已
Relax. He's just a friend.
我们要一起做口头报告
We're doing an oral report together.
他人很好啦
He's really nice.
抱歉  你刚说什么
I'm sorry, what was that?
我刚听到"口"字  微中风了一下
I had a little stroke after "oral."
你别乱想了
Would you stop?
人家只是刚从伦敦搬来啦
Look, he just moved here from London, okay?
他还没什么其他朋友
He doesn't really know anybody.
爽了  有英国腔的
Oh, good, an English accent,
-史上最性感的腔了  -才没有
- the sexiest accent you can have. - No.
才不是这样呢
That's not true.
还有法国腔  意大利腔
There's French, there's Italian.
好啦  你说得对  英国腔最棒
No, you're right, it's the best.
跟他说你有男朋友了吗
Did you tell him you have a boyfriend?
没谈到这话题
It didn't come up.
你跟他说嘛
Well, maybe you should tell him.
你要我怎么突然开口啊
What am I supposed to say?
就说  "现在没空聊
Say, "can't talk right now.
跟我男人在一起
hanging with my boyfriend.
英国去死  你去死  美国第一"
England sucks, you suck, USA number one."
行
Fine.
"跟我男人在一起
"Hanging with my boyfriend.
之后聊"  满意了吗
Talk to you later." Happy?
满意  谢谢
Yes. Thank you.
-他回了什么  -没什么
- What did he say? - Nothing.
说啊
What?
"是你男人逼你打出那段话的吗"
"Did your boyfriend make you type that?"
我讨厌这臭家伙
I hate this guy.
别这样嘛
Don't be like that.
拜托  相信我  他肯定是在泡你
Come on, trust me, he's hitting on you.
他才没泡我  我们只是朋友
No, he's not. We're just friends.
跟他搭档你会不开心吗
Look, is this gonna be a problem?
约好了他明天过来弄报告呢
Because he's supposed to come over tomorrow to work.
不是吧  来你家啊
Really? Here?
如果你会心里不舒坦  我可以换搭档
If it makes you uncomfortable, I'll switch partners,
虽然下周就得上台报告
even though the thing's due next week
而且大家都选好了固定搭档了
and everyone already has a partner
但为了你  挂科就挂科吧
and I'll probably end up failing the class.
太好了  谢谢你啊
That'd be great. Thank you.
2点44分  分秒不差
2:44, right on schedule.
谢尔顿
Hey, Sheldon.
你们好啊
Oh, hello.
拉杰跟我要去基因实验室
Raj and I are heading over to the genetics lab
摸摸夜光小兔子
to pet the glow-in-the-dark bunny.
-想跟我们一起去吗  -不用了  谢谢
- Want to come with us? - No, thank you.
你确定吗  关上实验室灯光
Are you sure? They turn off the lights,
那就是小型激光秀呢
and it's like a cute little laser show
差别只是它们会到处拉屎
that poops all over the place.
我确定  先走啦
I'm quite sure. Good day.
你要去哪啊
Well, where are you going?
-你们要去哪呢  -才刚告诉你啊
- Where are you going? - We just told you.
-我也才刚告诉你们  -你压根没说
- I just told you. - No, you didn't.
公说公有理  婆说婆有理  法庭见吧
Well, it's your word against mine; see you in court.
我们该跟踪他吗
Should we follow him?
不知道啊  我好纠结啊
I don't know, I'm torn.
既想知道他都上哪去
I want to know where he's going,
可又好想去摸摸小兔兔
but now I kind of want to play with the bunny.
你们好啊
Hi, guys.
艾利克斯  你知道你老板上哪去了吗
Hey, Alex, do you know where your boss just went?
不知道
No.
你应该知道他的行程吧
Don't you know his schedule?
他只交代  灯芯裤摩擦声太吵
All I know is corduroy makes too much noise
让我去换件"安静点的裤子"
and I have to go find "quieter pants."
来吧
Come on.
我愿意付出一切
Boy, what I wouldn't give
只求她能脱下裤子
to get her out of those pants...
换上一件更潮的裤子
and into something a little more stylish.
他就是来这里啊
This is where he goes?
里面有什么啊
What's in there?
这是旧储藏间吧
I think it's an old storage room.
什么事能让他每天躲在里面弄20分钟啊
What could he be doing in there every day for 20 minutes?
肯定不是"20分钟练腹肌运动"
Well, he's not doing 20-minute abs,
他要是有做的话  腹肌绝对好很多
because if he were, he would have way better abs.
-能听到什么吗  -没呢
- Can you hear anything? - Not yet.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
我也听啊
I'm listening.
你不能脸朝另一边听吗
Can't you face the other way and listen?
我做什么你都看不顺眼  是吧
I can't do anything right for you, can I?
他到底躲里面干啥呢
What the hell is he up to?
他是个怪人
He is kind of a weirdo.
说不定把伦纳德·尼莫伊五花大绑在里面
Maybe he's got Leonard Nimoy chained up in there.
或比尔·盖茨
Or Bill Gates.
甚至是史提芬·霍金呢
Or Stephen Hawking.
史提芬·霍金有什么好五花大绑啊
Why would he chain up Stephen Hawking?
霍华德  你不能因为人家是残疾人
Howard, please, you can't treat the man differently
就差别待遇啊  歧视是不对的
just because he's disabled. That's not okay.
你要是对于
If you're wondering why
我为何要直盯着窥视孔外有疑惑
I've been staring through the peephole,
我是要看看那个
I'm trying to get a look at this guy
要来佩妮家的男人
who's coming over to Penny's.
老实说  我都没注意到你在那边
To be honest, I didn't know you were here.
不是什么大事啦
It's not a big deal.
他只是她历史课的同学
He's just in her history class.
他们要一起弄报告
They're working on a project together.
我干嘛这么紧张兮兮啊
I don't even know why I care.
好吧  我不管了
You know what, I don't care.
自欺欺人而已
You think you don't care.
这样太蠢了
This is silly.
我没什么好担心的
I have nothing to worry about.
这可说不准
Oh, I don't know.
从数据上来看
Statistically speaking,
我肯定你的确有要担心的事
I'm sure you have something to worry about.
什么意思
What do you mean?
假设你的外貌是算中等
Well, if we assume your looks are average,
随便一算
right off the bat,
地球上有一半的男人比你还有魅力
50% of men on Earth are more attractive than you.
代表着有15亿帅气男子在等着
That's 1.5 billion handsome lads standing by,
浇熄你们的爱火呢
waiting to rain on your parade.
但爱情不是只看外貌啊
Well, yeah, but this isn't just about looks.
我也有很多部分是高于平均值啊
I'm way above average in a lot of other things.
绝非在身高  视力  运动能力
Not height, vision, athleticism,
或消化乳制品这几个领域吧
or ability to digest dairy products.
我是重要的项目赢别人啊
I'm talking about important things
例如感情成熟度
like emotional maturity.
你刚还从那小孔想探查你女友
You were just spying on your girlfriend through a peephole.
我还是比较喜欢你以为我不在那会
I liked it better when you thought I wasn't here.
我也不是说你就没有吸引人的优点
I'm not saying you don't have attractive qualities.
你的择友能力无懈可击
Your choice of friends is impeccable,
睡觉安稳不吵闹
you're a good sleeper.
再提一点
And last but not least,
你懂得买我喜欢的那种葡萄
you buy the grapes I like.
你也算是乘龙佳婿了
You're a real catch
大胜那些睡觉打鼾
compared to some snoring guy
满冰箱垃圾葡萄的人了
with a fridge full of lousy grapes.
无所谓啦
None of this matters.
我相信佩妮在乎我
I trust that Penny cares about me,
她也不会跟这男的有什么
and nothing's gonna happen with this guy.
如果他是催眠大师  那可说不准
Well, unless of course he's a skilled hypnotist.
什么
What?
虽然很难碰上  但也不是不可能啊
While unlikely, it's still a statistical possibility.
她现在可能正
She might be performing
无意识的与他发生性行为呢
sexual acts with him and not even know it.
你扯过头了吧
Now you're just being ridiculous.
你确定吗
Am I?
人的意识是很神奇的  莱纳德
The mind's a mysterious thing, Leonard.
那男的可能正一边"爽歪歪"
He could be having the time of his life
而佩妮只以为自己是吃玉米的鸡呢
while she thinks she's a chicken pecking for corn.
瞧咱俩  大半夜鬼鬼祟祟的来这里
Look at us, sneaking around in the middle of the night
像是一对飞贼一样
like a couple of cat burglars.
我们比较像忍者吧
I think we're more like ninjas.
我不想当忍者  人家想当飞贼
I don't want to be a ninja; I want to be a cat burglar.
行  我当忍者  你当飞贼
Fine, I'll be a ninja, you be a cat burglar.
不行  咱俩得一样
No, we both have to be the same thing.
好吧  我们都是忍者
Okay, we're ninjas.
谢谢
Thank you.
但下次我们要一起当飞贼哦
But next time, we'll be cat burglars.
-上锁了  -你确定吗
- It's locked. - Are you sure?
我当然确定
Yes, I'm sure.
你去把风  我来...
Now, you stand guard, I'm going to...
锁上了
It's locked.
去把风就行了
Just keep an eye out.
我很快就能弄开了
I'll have this open in a minute.
你什么时候学的开锁啊
When did you learn how to pick locks?
我中学那会开始学的魔术嘛
When I was starting to do magic in junior high,
当时我想当个逃脱魔术师
I thought I could be an escape artist
像逃脱大师胡迪尼一样
like Harry Houdini.
后来如何了
How did that work out?
挺不错啊
Pretty good.
朋友  人缘  以及我家方圆12英里内
I managed to escape friends, popularity,
所办的任何派对  都"逃脱"我而去了
and every party thrown in a 12-mile radius.
开了  准备好进去了吗
There. Ready?
-慢着慢着  -干嘛
- Hold on, hold on. - What?
谢尔顿是个非常聪明的人
Sheldon is a very smart man,
而且显然他想守住这个秘密
and he obviously wants to keep this a secret.
是啊  那又怎样
Yeah, so?
万一有机关陷阱怎么办
What if it's booby-trapped?
别担心  我早就想到了
Don't worry, I'm one step ahead of him.
那好  你有什么计...
Great, what's your pl...
没事吧
Are we good?
没事
Yeah.
Forty-three.
这到底是什么意思呀
What the hell does that mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
方程式的答案吗
The solution to an equation?
可能是
Maybe.
它是质数
It's a prime number.
加密系统就是基于素数的函数
Encryption systems are built on prime numbers.
谢尔顿有什么秘密是需要加密的啊
What kind of secret does Sheldon have to encrypt?
他的鸡蛋沙拉啊
He's always been very cagey about
他一直对让其美味的秘方三箴其口
what he puts in his egg salad to make it so tasty.
其实就是红辣椒
It's paprika.
真的吗
Really?
好吧  解决了一个谜题
Well, okay, one mystery solved.
晚安
Okay, good night.
谢谢啦  科尔
Thanks, Cole.
-学校见  -再见
- See you at school. - See you.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
我以为你早走了呢
I thought you left a long time ago.
你好吗
What's up?
你要搬到五楼的公寓住吗
You moving into the apartment on the fifth floor?
不  我是来看朋友的
No, I was just visiting a friend.
好吧
Oh, cool.
那个四楼的金发美女吗
That cute blonde on four?
对  你认识她吗
Yeah. You know her?
我见过她
I, well, I see her around.
我习惯跟她保持距离
I like to keep my distance
因为她男人超可怕的呢
because her boyfriend is a pretty scary dude.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
他是帮派份子
He's ganged up.
她跟我说  他是一名科学家
She told me he's a scientist.
那是他帮派的名字
That's the name of his gang.
"科学家"
The Scientists.
他们丧心病狂啊
They are crazy.
谢谢你的忠告
Well, thanks for the tip.
别客气  兄弟  别轻举妄动哦
No problem, brother. Stay frosty.
我们还是情侣  对吧
We're still dating, right?
你好呀  霍夫斯塔德博士
Oh, hello, Dr. Hofstadter.
艾利克斯  叫我莱纳德吧
Hey, Alex, and call me Leonard.
霍夫斯塔德博士是我爸
Dr. Hofstadter is my father.
还有我妈
And my mother.
我姐
And my sister.
跟我们家的猫
And our cat.
虽然我很确定
Although, I'm pretty sure
靴猫·霍夫斯塔德博士的只是荣誉学位
Dr. Boots Hofstadter's degree was honorary.
能一起坐吗  莱纳德
May I join you, Leonard?
-当然  -谢谢
- Sure. - Thanks.
艾利克斯  我问件事
Hey, Alex, let me ask you something.
我女朋友在学校认识个男的
My girlfriend knows this guy at school.
他有英国腔
He's got an English accent.
我爱死英国腔了
Ooh, I love English accents.
是啊  你们女人都爱
Yeah, you all do.
总之我觉得他在追她
Anyway, I feel like he's hitting on her.
她说他只是待人友善而已  让我相信她
She says he's just being nice and that I should trust her.
应该没事的
It's probably harmless.
你也懂的嘛
You know how it is.
我相信您肯定常有人追
I'm sure you get hit on all the time.
是啊
Right.
因为女孩子都会这样
Because girls are always like,
"那家伙有两套《星际迷航》的制服
"Ooh, that guy owns two Star Trek uniforms
而且耳部还经常受感染
"and gets a lot of ear infections.
我得把他搞到手啊"
I got to get me some of that."
我不知道
I don't know,
我敢说肯定常有人暗恋你
I bet it happens more than you realize.
相信我  真的没有
Trust me, it doesn't.
你确定吗
You sure?
你可爱又风趣
You're cute, you're funny.
说不定正有人追你  你却浑然不知
Maybe you're getting hit on, and you don't even know it.
真的吗
Really?
我挺确定呢
I'm pretty sure
好了  我得回去干活了
Okay, I got to get back to work.
谢谢你听我说
Thanks for listening.
没关系
No problem.
希望不会有妹子在半路冲上来把我扒光啊
Hope-hope no girls rip my clothes off on the way.
快想  我们都是聪明人
Come on, we're smart guys.
-我们一定能想出来  -43
- We can figure this out. - Forty-three.
什么是43
What is 43?
除了我妈妈脖子的尺寸
Besides my mom's neck size.
是锝的原子序数
It's the atomic number for technetium.
那玩意有放射性
That stuff's radioactive.
你觉得他是在造炸弹吗
Do you think he's building a bomb?
他花了两年时间才拼好
It took him two years to put together
乐高的积木死星  我不担心这个问题
that Lego Death Star; I'm not worried.
会不会是这个呢
Ooh, this could be something.
43是半杯
43 is the number of calories
无脂肪酸奶的卡路里数
in half a cup of fat-free yogurt.
你为什么会知道这个
Why would you know that?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
不是每个人胡吃海喝  都能像你那样不长肉
We can't all eat whatever we want and still stay thin.
等等  在《银河系漫游指南》中
Wait, in the Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy,
生命  宇宙和一切问题的答案
isn't 43 the answer to the question
不正好是43吗
of life, the universe, and everything?
那是42  蠢货
That's 42, dumb-ass.
好伤人哦
Feelings.
我们别再猜了
We should stop.
-我已经精疲力竭了  -我也是
- I'm exhausted. - Yeah, me, too.
我们还有更重要的事要做
We've got more important things to do.
谁在乎这个傻逼43是什么意思
Who cares what stupid 43 means?
-我不在乎  -我们回家吧
- Not me. - Let's go home.
想去吃点东西吗
You want to get something to eat?
好主意
Sounds good.
43到底是个啥玩意
What the balls is 43?!
老子一定要猜到
I have to know!
你不是应该和你的帮派混在一起
Hey, shouldn't you be out with your gang,
在大楼的墙上涂鸦方程式吗
spray painting equations on the side of buildings?
别这样  对不起
Come on, I'm sorry.
我只是不敢相信你居然不信任我
I just can't believe you don't trust me.
我当然信任你
I do, of course I do.
那为什么让我在朋友面前丢人
Then why did you embarrass me in front of my friend,
对了  他完全知道你是谁
who, by the way, knew exactly who you were?
-真的吗  -你的照片就贴在我家冰箱上
- Really? - Your picture's on my refrigerator.
我真的开始讨厌这家伙了
You know, I'm really starting to not like this guy.
你什么毛病啊
What is your problem?
上班时把脑子用没了
Do you use up all your thinking at work
回家后就只剩空脑壳了吗
and then have none left over for when you get home?
我不知道
I don't know.
有时候真的挺难受的
It's hard sometimes.
你去哪里
Everywhere you go,
都有男人想追你  哪怕我就站在旁边
guys hit on you, even if I'm standing right there.
而且他们都比我高
And they're all taller than me.
为什么每个人都比我高
Why is everyone taller than me?
这种事在我脑子里挥之不去
You know what, this is all in my head.
这是我的问题  不是你的
It's my problem, not yours.
莱纳德  你怎么总是这样
Leonard, why do you always do this?
听我说  我是和你在一起
Listen to me, you're the one I'm with.
你知道我爱你  别胡思乱想
You know I love you, so will you please relax
我快被你逼疯了
because you're driving me crazy.
这是你第一次说你爱我
You know that's the first time you ever said that you love me.
是的
Yeah.
我们要装作没什么大不了的吗
We're just supposed to pretend it's not a big deal?
这
That's...
正是我们要做的  因为
exactly what we're gonna do because...
你害我要哭鼻子了
you're about to make me cry,
我们都知道  如果我开始哭
and we both know if I start crying,
你也会开始哭
you're gonna start crying.
-没错  你该走了  -好的
- You're right, you should go. - All right.
她爱我
She loves me.
"你好  我是艾利克斯
"Hey, it's Alex.
很高兴和你一起喝咖啡
Nice having coffee with you.
如果你想继续聊天  我随时有空
If you want to talk more, I'm always available.
笑脸  笑脸"
Smiley face, smiley face."
这女生真友善啊
What a friendly girl.
有画面了
Okay, picture's up.
摄像头运作正常
Looks like the camera's working.
视频的清晰度真高啊
That's good quality video.
那当然  这是"火星漫游者"的备用摄像头
It better be. It's the spare camera for the Mars rover.
你是怎么弄到手的
How did you get your hands on that?
百万元的摄像头
Million dollar camera--
十块钱的锁
ten dollar lock.
我的天  他来了
Oh, my God, here he comes.
答案即将揭晓
This is it.
那是什么鬼东西
What the hell is that thing?
不知道
I don't know.
我是谢尔顿·库珀博士
This is Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
实验日志
Experimental log.
虫洞制造器第44次测试
Wormhole generator test 44.
虫洞制造器测试
Wormhole generator test?
之前的43个平行宇宙
The first 43 parallel universes
经我查证空空如也
I've checked proved to be empty.
我看没原因怀疑
I see no reason to suspect
第44号宇宙会有任何的不同
universe number 44 will be any different.
上帝啊
Oh, my God!
我的老天爷
Holy crap!
它在吃我的脸
It's eating my face!
那个东西在吃他的脸
It's eating his face!
我发现了摄像头  调包了视频讯号
I found your Webcam and replaced the video feed.
你们俩应该为自己的行为感到羞耻
You two should be ashamed of yourselves.
谢尔顿  真的对不起
Sheldon, we're really sorry.
真的对不起
Yeah, really sorry.
对不起
Sorry?
你们可能没意识到
You may not realize it,
但我每天的生活  都有不易驾驭的方面
but I have difficulty navigating certain aspects of daily life.
得理解讽刺的言语
You know, understanding sarcasm,
假装对他人的事感兴趣
feigning interest in others,
不能随心所欲地谈论火车
not talking about trains as much as I want to.
这让我心力交瘁
It's exhausting.
正因如此  每天有20分钟
Which is why, for 20 minutes a day,
我要去那个房间
I like to go down to that room,
什么都不想
turn my mind off
做自己喜欢的事来充电
and do what I need to do to recharge.
但你都在里面干嘛呢
But what are you doing in there?
43到底是什么意思
And what does 43 mean?
你们不需要知道
You don't need to know,
你们不配知道
you don't deserve to know,
你们永远都不会知道
and you will never know.
至少我知道你的鸡蛋沙拉是怎么做的了
Yeah, well I know how to make your egg salad now.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four,
五  六  七  八
five, six, seven, eight...
见鬼
Drat.
看来是再也踢不到43下了
I'm never going to get to 43 again.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four...
讨厌
Rats.